<PubmedArticle>
<MedlineCitation Owner="NLM" Status="MEDLINE">
<PMID Version="1">24618382</PMID>
<DateCompleted>
<Year>2014</Year>
<Month>11</Month>
<Day>07</Day>
</DateCompleted>
<DateRevised>
<Year>2014</Year>
<Month>03</Month>
<Day>12</Day>
</DateRevised>
<Article PubModel="Print">
<Journal>
<ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1925-6523</ISSN>
<JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
<Volume>34</Volume>
<Issue>1</Issue>
<PubDate>
<Year>2014</Year>
<Month>Feb</Month>
</PubDate>
</JournalIssue>
<Title>Chronic diseases and injuries in Canada</Title>
<ISOAbbreviation>Chronic Dis Inj Can</ISOAbbreviation>
</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An environmental scan of policies in support of chronic disease self-management in Canada.</ArticleTitle>
<Pagination>
<MedlinePgn>55-63</MedlinePgn>
</Pagination>
<Abstract>
<AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The evidence supporting chronic disease self-management warrants further attention. Our aim was to identify existing policies, strategies and frameworks that support self-management initiatives.</AbstractText>
<AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This descriptive study was conducted as an environmental scan, consisting of an Internet search of government and other publicly available websites, and interviews with jurisdictional representatives identified through the Health Council of Canada and academic networking.</AbstractText>
<AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We interviewed 16 representatives from all provinces and territories in Canada and found 30 publicly available and relevant provincial and national documents. Most provinces and territories have policies that incorporate aspects of chronic disease self-management. Alberta and British Columbia have the most detailed policies. Both feature primary care prominently and are not disease specific. Both also have provincial level implementation of chronic disease self-management programming. Canada's northern territories all lacked specific policies supporting chronic disease self-management despite a significant burden of disease.</AbstractText>
<AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Engaging patients in self-management of their chronic diseases is important and effective. Although most provinces and territories have policies that incorporate aspects of chronic disease self-management, they were often embedded within other initiatives and/or policy documents framed around specific diseases or populations. This approach could limit the potential reach and effect of self-management.</AbstractText>
</Abstract>
<AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
<Author ValidYN="Y">
<LastName>Liddy</LastName>
<ForeName>C</ForeName>
<Initials>C</Initials>
<AffiliationInfo>
<Affiliation>Bruyère Research Institute, C.T. Lamont Primary Health Care Research Centre, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada; University of Ottawa, Department of Family Medicine, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
</AffiliationInfo>
</Author>
<Author ValidYN="Y">
<LastName>Mill</LastName>
<ForeName>K</ForeName>
<Initials>K</Initials>
<AffiliationInfo>
<Affiliation>Bruyère Research Institute, C.T. Lamont Primary Health Care Research Centre, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
</AffiliationInfo>
</Author>
</AuthorList>
<Language>eng</Language>
<Language>fre</Language>
<PublicationTypeList>
<PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType>
<PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
<PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
</PublicationTypeList>
</Article>
<MedlineJournalInfo>
<Country>Canada</Country>
<MedlineTA>Chronic Dis Inj Can</MedlineTA>
<NlmUniqueID>101556266</NlmUniqueID>
<ISSNLinking>1925-6515</ISSNLinking>
</MedlineJournalInfo>
<CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
<MeshHeadingList>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic" UI="D000416">Alberta</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic" UI="D001955">British Columbia</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D002908">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName>
<QualifierName MajorTopicYN="Y" UI="Q000628">therapy</QualifierName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D005260">Female</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D019538">Health Care Surveys</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="Y" UI="D006291">Health Policy</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D006801">Humans</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D008297">Male</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D009313">National Health Programs</DescriptorName>
<QualifierName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="Q000458">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="Y" UI="D017063">Outcome Assessment (Health Care)</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D010353">Patient Education as Topic</DescriptorName>
<QualifierName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="Q000458">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D011050">Policy Making</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D011320">Primary Health Care</DescriptorName>
<QualifierName MajorTopicYN="Y" UI="Q000458">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName>
</MeshHeading>
<MeshHeading>
<DescriptorName MajorTopicYN="N" UI="D012648">Self Care</DescriptorName>
</MeshHeading>
</MeshHeadingList>
<OtherAbstract Language="fre" Type="Publisher">
<AbstractText Label="TITRE">Analyse contextuelle des politiques à l’appui de l’auto-prise en charge des maladies chroniques au Canada.</AbstractText>
<AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Les données probantes appuyant l’auto-prise en charge des maladies chroniques méritent de faire l’objet d’une analyse plus approfondie. Notre objectif était de cerner les politiques, les stratégies et les cadres existants à l’appui des initiatives d’auto-prise en charge.</AbstractText>
<AbstractText Label="MÉTHODOLOGIE">La présente étude descriptive a été effectuée sous forme d’analyse contextuelle. Elle comprend une recherche sur les sites Web gouvernementaux et d’autres sites Web accessibles au public ainsi que des entrevues avec des représentants gouvernementaux choisis par l’entremise du Conseil canadien de la santé et par réseautage universitaire.</AbstractText>
<AbstractText Label="RÉSULTATS">Nous avons interviewé 16 représentants de toutes les provinces et de tous les territoires du Canada et nous avons relevé 30 documents provinciaux et nationaux d’intérêt accessibles au public. La plupart des provinces et des territoires possèdent des politiques dont certains éléments portent sur l’auto-prise en charge des maladies chroniques. Les politiques de l’Alberta et de la Colombie-Britannique sont les plus détaillées. Elles accordent une place de choix aux soins primaires et elles ne sont pas axées sur une maladie en particulier. Elles présentent également des mesures pour la mise en oeuvre à l’échelle provinciale des programmes d’auto-prise en charge des maladies chroniques. L’ensemble des territoires du nord du Canada n’avait pas de politiques précises sur l’auto-prise en charge des maladies chroniques, malgré un lourd fardeau associé à ces maladies.</AbstractText>
<AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Faire participer les patients à l’auto-prise en charge de leur maladie chronique est important et efficace. Même si la plupart des provinces et des territoires possèdent des politiques qui comportent des éléments liés à l’auto-prise en charge des maladies chroniques, ces politiques sont souvent intégrées à d’autres initiatives ou d’autres documents de politiques axés sur des maladies ou des populations en particulier, ce qui peut limiter la portée et l’effet potentiels de l’auto-prise en charge.</AbstractText>
</OtherAbstract>
<KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
<Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic disease self-management</Keyword>
<Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">environmental scan</Keyword>
<Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health policy</Keyword>
<Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primary care</Keyword>
<Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-management support</Keyword>
</KeywordList>
</MedlineCitation>
<PubmedData>
<History>
<PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
<Year>2014</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>13</Day>
<Hour>6</Hour>
<Minute>0</Minute>
</PubMedPubDate>
<PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
<Year>2014</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>13</Day>
<Hour>6</Hour>
<Minute>0</Minute>
</PubMedPubDate>
<PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
<Year>2014</Year>
<Month>11</Month>
<Day>8</Day>
<Hour>6</Hour>
<Minute>0</Minute>
</PubMedPubDate>
</History>
<PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
<ArticleIdList>
<ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24618382</ArticleId>
</ArticleIdList>
</PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>